Guide to the History of Biosciences research materials, 2019-2021 UA 445
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
History of Biosciences research materials
2019-2021
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Matthews, Kathleen S.
UA 445
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collection mainly consists of the research materials for the "History of Biosciences" written by Kathleen Matthews.
Biographical / Historical
In 2019, Dr. Kathleen Matthews began compiling research materials documenting the history of Biosciences at Rice University. By 2021, she had written a finished manuscript entitled "History of Biosciences."
Content Description
This collection mainly consists of the research materials for the "History of Biosciences" written by Kathleen Matthews. It also includes a draft of the History of Biosciences.
Conditions Governing Access
The majority of the collection is open for research. Restricted items are labeled in the inventory.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Index Terms
Subjects
Life sciences; Rice University -- History; Universities and colleges
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Draft and Appendix research
  - Draft, 2021-05 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appendix 1a source: A University So Conceived, 2006 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Appendix 1b source: William March Rice and His Institute, 2012 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Appendix draft, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appendices research 2 - 47, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appendices research 48 - 72, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Appendices research 72 - 77, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Appendices research 78 - 86, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Appendices research 87 - 93, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appendices research 94 - 117, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appendices research 118 - 131, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appendices research 132 - 154, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appendices research 155 - 164, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appendices research 165 - 188, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Research organized by topic
  - Huxley, Julian (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Faculty (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Altenburg, Edgar (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Faculty biographies (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Faculty info A - F (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty info G - P (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty info P - R (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Faculty info S - Z (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brochures - Biochemistry (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Exams by decades (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General announcements (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology - History: 1972-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Nobels / Rice Leadership (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lovett, Edgar O.: 1915-1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lovett, Edgar O.: 1928-1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Biology building: 1953-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pitzer, Kenneth: 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faculty - Pitzer - late 1960s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Biology struggle: 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Beginning of Biochemistry: 1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Thresher articles - Faculty and teaching awards (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hackerman, Norman: 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hackerman, Norman: 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Biochemistry: 1972-mid-1980s (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Biochemistry: 1978-1998 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology brochures: 1989- (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology - Annual reports and plans: 1989-2017 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Images and bios (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Research faculty: 1977-2004 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Faculty feedback (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bioscience Research Collaborative: 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Interviews (CD) (Restricted) (Box 2, Folder 31)